怎么盒子和盖子的数量不对应呢
How could we don't have the same number of containers and lids?
它们怎么会分开呢
Why would they ever get separated?
可能感情不和 也可能经济问题
Built-up resentment, money issues,
还可能跟年轻的盖子跑了
met a younger lid.
妈妈 我的科学作业哪去了
Mom, where's my science homework?
就在那边的桌子上
Uh, it's over there on the table.
艾丽克斯 宝贝 最近怎么样
So, Alex, honey, what's going on?
有啥新鲜事吗
Anything exciting?
没有
No.
-有喜欢的男孩吗 -没有
- Any boys? - No.
我觉得我和艾丽克斯之间
I'm feeling a little bit disconnected
有代沟了
from Alex right now.
就在上周
Last week, I picked up her cellphone,
我错拿了她的手机
thinking it was mine.
无意中看到几条暧昧短信
And I accidentally read a few flirty text messages
如果是她班上的某个男生干的
that were probably from a boy in her class,
那也就罢了
which is fine.
就怕是哪个混混发的
Or they're from a drifter.
来嘛 你就真没啥
Come on, isn't there something
要告诉你"马马"的吗
you want to share with your mommers?
有 别自称"马马"
Yeah. Don't call yourself "Mommers."
盒子想上盖子 盖子爆发了
He blew his lid when she tried to contain him.
你觉得这件怎么样
Okay. What do you think?
-我喜欢 -但不是特别喜欢
-I like it. -But you don't love it.
谁说的 我爱死它了
No, I do. I love it.
-和刚才那件比 -天
- As much as you loved the other one? - Ooh.
好吧
Okay. Mm.
房子着火了 我只来得及拿一件衬衫
The house is on fire. I only have time to grab one shirt.
我选谁
Which one do I take?
带上莉莉才是正解
The correct answer is take Lily.
那之后呢
After that.
好吧 拿蓝色的那件
Uh, okay, the blue one.
因为我穿灰色的显胖
Because the gray one washes me out.
不不不 别误会 小卡
No, no. Cam, you -- you can't go wrong here.
你不管穿什么都美翻了
Everything you've tried on looks great.
两件都好搭你
I love you in both of them.
还是你疼我
Oh, you're so nice to me.
米奇尔不喜欢在公众场合亲热
Mitchell has a problem with public displays of affection.
我记得有一年的新年派对上
Um, I remember once at a new year's eve party,
零点钟声一响 他和我击掌庆祝
stroke of midnight, he high-fived me.
两个问题
Two problems with that --
首先 同志不击掌
One, gays don't high-five.
其次 同志不击掌
Two, gays don't high-five.
我回来啦
I'm home!
烧什么呢这么香
Mmm, what smells so good?
我在做圈圈肉 哥伦比亚名菜呢
I'm making chunchullo, a traditional Colombian dish,
为了今晚的家庭聚餐准备的
for dinner with the family tonight.
圈圈肉
Chunchullo.
那是啥 跟玉米卷差不多吗
What is that -- like, uh, tacos?
对 就跟玉米卷似的
Yes, like tacos.
才不是呢
No, it isn't.
-这是猪肠做的 -我的老天爷
- It's the small intestine of a pig. - Oh, Geez.
我们就不能像其他人一样吃正常点儿吗
Why can't we eat regular food like normal people?
我跟你说过滴 杰
I told you, Jay.
我那远在天国的奶奶
My grandmother, who rests in peace,
曾经托梦给我
has been coming to me in my dreams,
告诫我不要忘本
telling me that I'm losing touch with my roots.
你看 这下尴尬了
See, this is awkward,
因为我死了的叔叔告诉我今晚该吃牛排
because my dead uncle joe told me to have steak tonight.
不不不 杰 放尊重点
No, no, no, Jay. Have some respect.
我奶奶能听见你滴
My grandmother can hear you.
什么意思 她能听到我们吗
What do you mean, she can hear us?
是这样滴 在我们的文化里
Well, in our culture,
我们相信死者的灵魂就在我们身边
we believe that the dead are all around us.
她说的对 曼尼
She's right, Manny.
可能现在她就在你背后
She could be right here,
从坟墓里伸出她那瘦骨嶙峋的手指
her bony fingers reaching out from the grave.
厉害哦 杰 继续忽悠呀
Yeah, keep it up, Jay.
这房子里已经有一个死人了
There's already one dead person in this room.
你也想死是哇
You want to make it two?
我错了 我去装打印机
I'm sorry. I've got a printer to install.
歌洛莉亚 麻烦让你奶奶
Oh, Gloria, have your grandmother
十分钟后给我拿杯冰红茶来
run me up an iced tea in about 10 minutes.
是啊 她要活着滴话干得比你好
Yeah, she has a better chance of making that work than you!
你打电话给菲尔啊 省得一会你搞砸了又叫又骂
Why don't you save us the stomping and the swearing and call Phil?
他这方面比较牛
He's good at that stuff.
能有我牛
Better than me?
菲尔任何方面都没我牛
Phil's not better than me at anything,
他也就只会怪叫啥的
Except maybe making that stupid sound with his mouth.
咋 咋样
A what, what
你口水喷我脸上了
You spit on me.
宝贝海莉 来帮我个忙
Haley, honey, um, I need you to do something for me.
啊 妈 我手痛
Ugh. Mom, my arm hurts.
你都不知道我找你啥事
Why don't you find out what it is
着急编瞎话干嘛
before you start making up excuses to get out of it?
好吧 说吧
Okay, what is it?
我要你去和你妹妹谈谈
I need you to talk to your sister.
我觉得她和某个男孩子有暧昧
I think that there's something going on with her and a boy.
然后
So?
然后 我是你们的妈妈
So, I am your mother, and it is my job to make sure
确保你们不被坏蛋给剥皮吃了
that you girls don't get involved with a predator.
得了吧 妈妈 别再看新闻联播了
Okay, mom, stop watching "Dateline."
你自己怎么不去和她谈
And why can't you just talk to her?
我试过了
I have tried to talk to her.
她不会跟我开口的 你懂的
I -- she won't talk to me. You know that.
因为一有男孩接近我们你就变得神经质
That's because you get so weird every time a boy comes near us.
我只是不想你们这些女孩子
I-I just don't want you girls to --
-重蹈你的覆辙吗 -不是
- To make the same mistakes that you did? - No!
当然不是
No.
老妈 我又不傻
Mom, I'm not an idiot.
我看得出来
I pick up on things.
你可不是你口中描述的
And I don't think that you were the good girl
那种好女孩
you pretend you were.
天哪 你大错特错了
Wow. That is so untrue.
你不知道我以前有多乖
I was a very good girl. Mm.
孩子不需要知道
Your kids don't need to know
他们只需了解你想要的完美形象
They need to know who you wish you were,
还必须以你为榜样
and they need to try to live up to that person.
他们可能达不到这个标准
They're gonna fall short,
但参照人物是虚构的完美的你
but better they fall short of the fake you
肯定比真实的你强
than the real you.
所以我们从不隐瞒
Which is why we don't hide anything.
你说的和我的刚好相反
That's the opposite of what I just said.
我溜号了
I was not listening.
我还得说一遍 我喜欢你穿这件佩斯利
I'll say it again -- I love you in paisley.
不如先关好门 拉好窗帘
Oh, let me lock the door and draw the curtains.
你什么意思
What does that mean?
-什么意思都没有 -很好
-It doesn't mean anything. -Good.
你当然知道我什么意思
You know exactly what it means.
你不在别人面前亲我
You won't kiss me in front of other people
是因为你不能正视自己
because you're ashamed of who you are.
没错 我就是戳你痛处了
And, yes...I went there.
你不能拿戳我当乐事
Okay, you can't say, "Yes, I went there,"
还企图用过去式
when you go there all the time.
再说了 每次飞机上有人对咱们另眼相待
And, by the way, I'm the one who makes speeches on airplanes
可都是我站出来教育他们
every time someone looks at us weird.
我爸爸说你是我"朋友"的时候
I'm the one who gives my dad hell
也是我跟他挑明挖烂了理论
when he refers to you as my "Friend."
那不一样 那是正面冲突
That's different. That's confrontation.
但你知道什么才最需要勇气吗
But you know what takes real strength?
抱怨吗
Whining?
-是表达爱意 -受不了了
-Affection. -Oh, this is insane.
买衬衫有什么可亲的
Buying a shirt -- it's not a kiss-worthy moment.
我不知道这还有官方规定
Oh, I didn't know there was an official list.
求你 告诉我 什么时候能亲
Please, tell us -- what is on the list?
我告诉你什么时候不亲吧
I'll tell you what's not on the list --
吃了夹辣椒的橄榄
Finding jalapeno-stuffed olives,
给枫树挂灯泡的时候
making the light on maple,
看到大众车的时候也不亲
every time we see a V.W.
你不喜欢玩"亲亲甲壳虫"[看到大众甲壳虫车就亲亲]
You don't like "Kiss-buggy"?
那根本就不是游戏
It's not a real game!
那不过是你黏人的一种方式
It -- it's just another way for you to be needy.
你可别想把我搞得很内疚
I -- and I don't appreciate you making me feel bad
因为我可达不到你那离谱的标准
because I can't live up to your impossible standards.
没人在保龄球馆接吻
Nobody kisses at a bowling alley!
我差点打出三击全中
I almost got a turkey!
侬好
"Yello"?
你好 杰 等下 我找克莱尔去
Oh, hey, Jay. Just a sec. I'll go get Claire.
其实我找你
Oh, actually, it's you I'm calling.
什么声音
What was that?
是猫 有只猫 什么事
The cat. There's a cat. What's up?
歌洛莉亚很想念她的外婆
Well, Gloria's been missing her grandmother.
我一直想打印出一张她的照片
I've been trying to get this old picture of her printed,
但是新的打印机 我...
but I can't get this new printer to --
我马上到
I'll be right there.
卢克 外公需要我们
Luke, grandpa needs us!
接到电话 我当然很高兴
Hells yes, I was glad to get the call.
杰总来我家修东西
Jay's always around here fixing things,
嘲笑我柔弱的双手
cracking jokes about my "Delicate hands"
还有我一闻油漆就吐
or my gag response to the smell of paint.
看看谁来求哥了
Look who needs me now
"手好粗"先生每次想按打印键
Mr. Hot-dog fingers who can't press "Print"
他那胖手都会多按好几个按钮
without hitting three extra keys.
真菜
Yeah!
你可是在我的主场 杰
You're in my house now, Jay!
准确的说 我要去他的地盘迎战
T-technically, we'll be in his house,
但是他的地盘
but we'll be in my area...
哥做主
of his house.
我听说你有男朋友了
So, I hear you have a boyfriend.
-哪有 -他是谁
- No, I don't. - Who is he?
-我才不告诉你呢 -说吧
- I'm not talking to you about this. - Oh, come on.
你总算有点八卦可挖了 快说呗
You're finally interesting. Just tell me.
他不是我男友
He's not my boyfriend.
他叫杰里米·瑞德
It's Jeremy Reed.
不过是个男孩 我...
It's -- he's just this boy that I --
-爱他 -没有
- Love? - No!
你们接吻了吗
Well, have you guys kissed yet?
没有
No!
那你等什么呢
Well, what are you waiting for?
我没等 人家才13岁
I'm not waiting. I'm 13.
你还没亲过男生
And you've never kiss boy?
你初吻什么时候
How old were you?
11岁的时候吧
Like 11.
唯美极了
And it was beautiful.
是在杰克逊·肯纳家铺了地毯的车库里
I was in Jackson Kaner's carpeted garage.
-11岁 -是啊
- 11? - Yeah.
你最好也抓紧
So you better get on it,
要不然他会觉得你是拉拉
or else he's gonna think you're a lesbian.
他才不会认为我是拉拉
He's not going to think I'm a lesbian.
我就以为你是
I thought you were.
你那凉鞋很拉拉
You totally have the sandals for it.
我们来看看出了什么问题
Let's see this bad boy.
P-750型 不错
Oh, a P-750. Nice unit.
要是我 会选840那款
I would have sprung for the 840,
但是我知道
But I get it --
不是谁都能玩转这种高级货的
not everyone can handle that kind of horsepower.
我以为是无线电话干扰了信号
I thought maybe the cordless phone was interfering,
我就给它拔了
so I unplugged it.
好主意 也许我们应该下楼
Good idea. Maybe we should run downstairs
把面包机也拔了
and unplug the toaster while we're at it.
幽默啊 老爸
Oh, snap, dad.
面包机
Toaster.
开玩笑
We're kidding.
无线电话是5.8千兆赫 这个是无线网络
A cordless phone is 5.8 gigahertz. This is wi-fi.
用的不是一个频谱
It's a totally different spectrum.
跟我来
Walk with me?
教克莱尔使用电器的时候 我发明了个小诀窍
Here's a little trick that I've found pretty useful with Claire.
电脑和打印机必须要交流 流 流
The computer and the printer must talk, talk, talk
command+p[苹果快捷键] 图片就出来了 了 了
command-p" Makes the picture walk, walk, walk"
好像没反应啊
How come it's not working?
不应该啊
It should be.
好吧
Okay.
应该开始打印了
Uh, that should be printing.
应该是...
So...
菲尔 在打的你头头头之前
Hey, Phil, I'm gonna get a beer, beer, beer
我要先喝杯啤酒酒酒
Before I hit you in the head, head, head.
嘿 有事吗
Hey. What are you doing here?
杰里米 我有问题想问你
Hi, Jeremy. I want to ask you something.
-好 问 -等等 你先别出声
- Sure, ask - Wait, don't talk yet.
是在这么回事
Here is the thing.
我们短信已经发了一段时间了 这样挺好
We've texting for a while, and it's been nice,
但我感觉我们不止于此
but I feel like it's leading to something else,
我不知道你有没有这种感觉
and I don't know if you do or not,
我要说的是
but I guess what I'm trying to say is,
我只是一个女孩 站在一个男孩面前
I'm just a girl standing in front of a boy
请他喜欢她
asking for him to like her.
不对 这句是《诺丁山》的台词
Oh, god, that's from "Notting hill."
太老套了 不过这绝对是部被低估的电影
So dorky. But a really underrated movie.
你想表达什么
What's happening?
我不是拉拉
I'm not a lesbian.
我想你亲我
I would like for you to kiss me.
我喜欢看你搅拌的样子
Oh, I love watching you stir.
那我就停下
Then I will stop.
怎么 你还生我的气
What? Are you still mad at me?
是 你要为取笑我滴文化 我滴信仰
Yes. You have to apologize for making fun of my culture, my beliefs,
我滴圈圈肉 我滴奶奶而道歉
my chunchullo, my abuela.
对不起
I'm sorry.
如果你认为你奶奶也在这里
If you think your Grandmother's here with us,
我表示尊重
I respect that.
来抱抱
Now, come here.
奶奶 你从哪冒出来的
Oh, Grandma! Where'd you come from?
看来我们要给你系个小铃铛才行
We're gonna have to get you a little bell.
够了 杰
Enough, Jay!
我的文化对我很重要
My culture is very important to me!
为了今晚跟你滴家人吃饭我忙了一整天
I've been working all day to share it with your family tonight,
你却只管嘲笑我
and all you do is mock me!
走开
Just go!
亲爱的 对不起
Honey, I'm sorry.
我只是逗你玩
I'm just teasing you.
有时间当小丑 干嘛不帮我
Instead of being the comedian, why don't you help me?
要我干什么
What do you need?
-拍鸡肉 -干什么
- Slap the chicken. - Do what?
在哥伦比亚 为了表示对死者的尊重
In Colombia, when you cook in honor of the departed,
烹饪前要把死神从食物吓走
you have to scare death away from the food
以保护将要吃此食物滴人
to protect the people that are gonna eat it.
一边拍一边叫
Slap it and yell.
那也太傻缺了
That's the nuttiest --
-杰 -淡定
-Jay! -Calm down.
鸡肉拿来
Give me the chicken.
拍就拍
Here we go.
介么轻什么也吓不跑
That's not scaring anything away.
以前我爷爷做饭滴时候
When my grandfather used to cook,
整间房子都在颤抖
the whole house would shake.
大声点
Louder.
调高点
Higher.
不够大声
Louder!
调再高 声再大 这才差不多
Higher! Louder! There!
我瞎编滴
I made all that up.
哥伦比亚没有这个习俗
That is not a real custom in Colombia.
我们又不是精神错乱
We're not lunatics.
但你惹姐不高兴 姐也不让你舒坦
But you mess with us, and we mess with you.
这才素我们的习俗
That's the custom.
大声点
Louder!
亲爱的 你去哪了
Hey, honey. Where'd you go?
哪也没去 就骑了会脚踏车
Nowhere. Just for a bike ride.
我的天 求求你告诉我这短信纯属虚构
Oh, my god! Puh-lease tell me this text is wrong!
你真跑去那个小屁孩的家
Did you really just go over to that kid's house
在众目睽睽之下跟他索吻
and try and kiss him in front of a million people?!
-艾丽克斯你真这么做了 -你收到短信爆料了
- Alex, did you do that? - You got a text?
当然 地球人都知道了
Oh, yeah. Everybody knows.
你知道这让我有多尴尬吗
Do you know how embarrassing this is for me?!
这都是你的错
This is all your fault!
是你说我如果不跟他接吻就是拉拉
You're the one who said I had to kiss him or I was a lesbian!
海莉 你真这么说了
Haley! Did you say that to her?!
别扯到我身上 你看她穿的那双鞋
Oh, don't turn this on me. Look at her shoes!
我永远都不要去上学了
Ugh! I'm never going back to school now.
不 亲爱的 你要 你要去上学
No, sweetheart. Yes, you are. You are going back to school.
但听我说 男生给你发暧昧短信
But listen to me-- Just because a boy sends you flirty texts.
并不表示
Doesn't mean that
-你要回复他 -什么 你偷看我短信
-you have to text him back - what?! You read my texts?!
-我... -你偷看她短信
- I... - You read her texts?!
这就是为什么你要我跟她谈
That's why you made me talk to her?!
是你让她跟我谈的
You made her talk to me?!
我觉得我们现在把话题扯远了
I kind of feel like we're spinning out here a little bit.
艾丽克斯 重点是
Look, Alex, the important thing here
你跟男生的交往要格外小心
Is that you have to be very careful how you behave around boys
要不你很容易就把名声给毁了
Because it is so easy to get a reputation.
我很抱歉我不像你是那么完美的乖乖女
Well, I'm sorry I'm not a perfect little good girl like you were!
你乖吗
Were you?
你乖吗?!
Were you?!
我严重怀疑
I highly doubt it!
胆子别这么小 这里根本没有什么鬼魂
Don't be such a chicken. There's no ghost in here.
我说真的 我妈说她过世的奶奶就在这
I'm telling you, my Mom said her dead grander was in the house.
她说她今天早上感觉到她的存在
She said she felt her here this morning...
就在这个房间
In this room.
也许你妈精神病
Maybe your Mom's mentally ill.
是哪个天刹的把路由器... 放在阁楼里
Who puts a router... in the attic?
她是不是腿脚不便 杵着一根枴杖
Did she have a limp and a cane?
曼尼曾祖母的鬼魂
Ghost of Manny's great-grandma,
如果真是你
if that's really you,
快快显灵
Show yourself!
这就是我曾祖母
That's her!
怎么会
Come on!
为什么
Why?!
为什么?!!
Why?!!
-外公好 -你们好吗 孩子们
-Hi, grandpa.- How we doing, girls?
我今天算是被妈妈毁了
Mom ruined my life today.
-我没有 我是 -不要和我说话
-I didn't ruin your life. I was - don't even talk to me!
我根本都不想来这
I didn't even want to come here.
好了
Well, okay.
点心和苏打水在客厅
Snacks and and sodas are in the living room,
别吃太饱 一会还要吃猪肠
But don't fill up -- we've got intestines coming.
那个 爸 如果你在找鞋
Uh, dad, if you're looking for your shoes,
我晓得在哪儿
I think I know where they are.
这是个哥伦比亚风俗
This happens to be a colombian custom --
追随祖先的足迹啥啥啥的
Walking in the footsteps of the ancestors, blah, blah, blah.
总比让我拍鸡肉好过
Beats slapping the chicken.
来 我给你拿了杯喝的
Here, I brought you a drink.
等一下
Oh, wait a minute --
你先喝一口
Sip it first.
我没生你气
I'm not mad at you.
我想了一下 也许你是对的
I thought about it, and maybe you're right.
有时候我是有点粘人了
I can be a little needy sometimes.
喔 谢谢你那么说
Oh, well, I-I appreciate that.
当然也不全是你的错
And you're probably not entirely off base.
我是说 天知道 我自己也很怪咖
I mean, lord knows I-I've got my quirks.
我不是个爱感情外露的人
And I-I'm not the most demonstrative guy around,
但是我在改
But I'm -- I'm working on it.
-我会帮你的 -好
-And I'm gonna help you with it. -Good.
别失去耐心
Just don't give up on me.
永远不会
Never.
大家伙都过来
Okay, everybody, let's gather around!
杰 过来
Jay, come here.
今晚我们吃传统哥伦比亚菜
Tonight we dine on the traditional colombian recipes
我奶奶的拿手菜 [abuela西班牙语里祖母的意思]
of my abuela, my grandmother.
尽管她已经不在了
And even though she's no longer with me,
但素我很高兴 因为我有你们
I am very happy because I have all of you.
为了我的祖母干杯[祖母名字不要太~长]
To ana-maria rosa de la immaculada jimenez morales.
为… 那谁干杯
To ana-maria rosa...
歌洛莉亚 太美好了
That was beautiful, Gloria,
就像我的米奇尔一样
just like my Mitchell.
好滑
Just slipped right off there.
卡梅隆 怎么了
Ay, Cameron, what happened?
刚才你还坐在那
One moment you were there,
一眨眼滴功夫就只看见鞋子了
the next, only shoes.
我告诉你是怎么回事
I'll tell you what happened --
米奇尔不好意思
Mitchell is embarrassed to kiss me
在别人面前吻我
in front of other people.
不是的 是你太突然了
No, you ambushed me!
小卡 算了吧
Oh, Cam, come on.
他不是针对你
Don't take it personally.
米奇尔上高中的时候
When Mitchell was in high school,
和一个叫罗宾·希尔的女孩约会
He was dating this girl -- Robin Schier.
他也从来不吻人家
He would never kiss her, either.
那是因为我是同志
That's because I was gay.
那现在你又有什么借口
What's your excuse now?
卡梅隆 这不怪米奇尔
Ay, Cameron, it's not Mitch's fault.
他遗传他爸
He gets it from his father.
杰也不喜欢在公共场合黏黏呼呼滴
Jay doesn't like the lovey-dovey in public, either.
简直不敢相信你又扯到我身上来了
I can't believe you're coming at me right now.
我现在站在这 脖子上还套着双鞋
I'm standing here with shoes around my neck.
有大半个钟头
And for the better part of a half-hour,
我都在大嚷着把肉里面的死神吓出来
I screamed the death out of your meat.
-你到底想让我怎么样 -看见了吧
-Now, what do you want from me? -Don't you see?
都是因为你
It's because of you
你儿子才不肯吻他情人的
that your son cannot kiss his own lover.
-不要说"情人" -我们不喜欢说"情人"
- Don't say "Lover." - we don't like "Lover."
我们吃饭好不好
Can we just eat?
不行 你告诉米奇尔
No. Tell Mitch
他可以当着你的面吻卡梅隆
that it's okay to kiss Cam in front of you.
干嘛非得这样
Why is that something we have to do?
不需要
We don't.
当然不需要
Of course we don't.
真对不起 我不想当着我全家人的面
Oh, I'm sorry that I don't want to make out with you
和你亲热
in front of my whole family.
不用道歉
No need to apologize.
歌洛莉亚说的对
Oh, Gloria is right.
爸爸 你这么封闭自己的感情
Dad, you being so emotionally closed off
影响了你的孩子也很难表达自己的感情
makes it very difficult for your children to show affection.
-是吗 -没错
- Really? - Yes.
你在公共场合也不善于表达感情
You had trouble showing affection in public places?
-对 -你吗 -是的
-Yes!- You? -Yes.
那是在你什么也没穿
Was that before or after
只穿着内衣 披着警察局的毯子
you were delivered to my door in a squad car,
被巡逻车送到我门口之前还是之后
wearing nothing but your underwear and a police blanket?
天哪 什么 你进去过
Oh, my god. What? You were arrested?
-太给力了 -给什么力
-Awesome! - Not awesome.
我没有被逮捕
And I wasn't arrested.
你们外公只是在开玩笑
Your grandfather was just telling a joke.
玩笑吗 我能讲N个呢
It was just a joke. I got a million of 'em.
爸爸
Dad.
我成功啦
I did it!
能打印了
It's printing!
我下载了新固件 安装了新的驱动程序
I had to download new firmware, install new drivers,
改了你的加密码 还在蒸笼似的阁楼上
change your encryption, and replace an ethernet cable
换了条以太网线缆
in a 100-degree attic,
一边还得防着点蜘蛛
while dodging particularly aggressive spiders,
但是我做到了
but I did it!
谢谢
Thanks.
喔 看来就这样了
Oh. Okay. I guess that's it.
什么 就怎么样了
What? What's it?
还不明白吗 傻瓜
Wake up, dummy.
这就是我们说的
This is what we're talking about.
这家伙像白痴一样给你忙活了一天
This guy's been working like an imbecile all day for you.
我们还需要别的东西 亲吻 拥抱
People need something else -- kisses, hugs.
什么 就为了修理个打印机吗
What, for fixing a printer?
也没什么 只用了四个小时
Oh, it's fine. It was only four hours.
我让一个油漆桶绊倒了 小吐了一下
I tipped over a paint can and threw up a little,
但是我想 我想这句"谢谢"也够了
But I think -- I think "Thanks" about covers it.
是啊 说"谢谢"怎么了
Well, what's wrong with "Thanks"?
爸爸 这几乎是最低程度的感激了
It's pretty much the bare minimum, dad.
杰 看在上帝份上 说点什么
Jay, for god's sakes, just say something.
你想让我说点什么吗
You want me to say something?
那"欢迎你们"怎么样
How about "You're welcome"?
"我很高兴你们大家都能来"
How about "I'm -- I'm so happy to be here for you all
"所以我才能在这享受你们的碎碎念"吗
so I can take the blame for all your crap."
我做不来
I don't do this,
我从来也不做这个
I never did that.
相信我 我给你们的已经比我父亲
Trust me, I gave you twice
给我的要多出一倍了
as much as my father ever gave me.
他一辈子就吻过我一次
The man kissed me one time in my entire life.
他走到我身后亲了下我的后脑勺
He came up behind me, kissed me on the back of the head,
对我说 晚安 贝奇
said, "Goodnight, Becky."
他竟然把我当成了我妹妹
He thought I was my sister.
等一下
Wait a minute.
你上次亲米奇是什么时候
When was the last time you kissed Mitch?
这都哪跟哪啊
What does that have to do with anything?
米奇 他上次亲你是什么时候
Mitch, when was the last time he kissed you?
我记不得了
I-I don't remember.
-又没多久 -我12岁的时候
- It wasn't that long ago. - I was 12.
12岁 这就是问题所在
12? This is the problem!
杰的老爸不亲杰
Jay's dad doesn't kiss Jay,
所以杰就不亲米奇 从而导致米奇灰常保守
so Jay doe't kiss Mitch, and Mitch is uptight.
好了好了 现在不是谈我保不保守的事
Okay, okay, "Uptight" was really not on the table.
我们是在谈亲吻
This is more about kissing.
杰 亲吻你的儿子 他简直一团糟
Jay, kiss your son. He's a mess.
不会吧 现在吗
Oh, come on, now.
我们其实不必这么做的
We don't have to do that. It's...
-你要做 - 不
- Yes, you do. - No. - Come on.
快滴 亲嘛 孙辈们都看着呢
Come on, do it. You're in front of your grandchildren.
好吧好吧 别吵了
All right, all right! Shut up!
米奇 过来
Mitch, get over here.
什么 现在吗 我觉得太诡异了
W-what, now? Well, I feel weird now.
别扭扭捏捏的
Don't be coy.
你还等什么呢 一盒巧克力吗
What are you waiting for, a box of chocolates?
过来亲亲
Let's do this.
这是我见过的最甜蜜的事了
That's the sweetest thing I've ever seen.
就这样 我现在可不想再听到有人抱怨
All right, and now because I never want to hear this again.
到你了
You.
没你的事
Not you.
爸爸我爱你
Oh, daddy, I love you.
我们来吃圈圈肉吧
Let's go eat chunchullo!
那是用猪肠做的对吗
You know it's made of pig intestines, right?
艾丽克斯 等一下
Alex, wait.
-怎么了 -我想和你谈谈
- What? - I want to talk to you.
妈妈 我不想再听你的那些说教了
Mom, I don't want another lecture.
不是说教 我想告诉你一些事情
It's not a lecture. I want to tell you something.
亲爱的 我完全了解你现在的心情
Honey, I know exactly how you're feeling.
不 你不了解
No, you don't.
好吧 还记得今晚外公讲的那个笑话吗
Okay, the -- the joke that grandpa told tonight?
确 确实有这么回事
That -- that happened.
那 是真的
That...That was true.
这么说你真裸着被抓过
So, you were arrested naked?
我没裸
I wasn't naked!
而且我本身也没有被抓
And I was not arrested per se.
我只是有天晚上被警车送回家
I was driven home one night by the police
而这是因为我和我男友
because my boyfriend and I
没带泳衣
had gone swimming in somebody's pool,
就跑去别人的水池里游泳等等等等
and we didn't have bathing suits and -- blah, blah, blah.
细节不重要
The details aren't important.
关键在于学校里每个人都在谈论这件事
What matters is that everybody at school was talking about it.
我当时以为自己死定了
And I thought I would die.
不过这事儿也就这么过去了
But it passed.
我发誓
I swear.
而现在 宝贝 我很高兴有这么回事
And now, honey, I'm -- I'm glad it happened.
这让我在晚宴时有笑料可说
I've got a funny story to tell at dinner parties.
那你花了多久才觉得这事儿有趣的
So, how long did it take before you thought it was funny?
老天
Oh, god...
十到十五年吧
10, 15 years.
好极了 我明天怎么办
Great. What do I do about tomorrow?
我认为你不需要担心这个
I don't think you have to worry about that.
去吧去吧
Go, go, go.
在哥伦比亚 我们常常亲吻
In Colombia, we kiss for everything,
因为一个吻可以有辣么多涵义
because a kiss can mean so many different things.
这儿没鬼吧
There's no ghost in here, is there?
当然没
Not a chance.
睡个好觉 孩子
Sleep easy, kid.
它可能素一个全新的开始
It can be the start of something new.
也可能素我们说"这是我的爱人"的方式
It can be how we say, "This is the person that I love."
谁吻功更高 我还是你老爸
So who's a better kisser, me or your dad?
恶[与"你"音相近]
Ew.
也可能会很浪漫
It can be romantic.
只是想告诉你 要是我朋友不在那儿的话
Just so you know, if my friends weren't there,
我会答应你的
I would've said yes.
所以 要是你还愿意的话
So, if you still want to...
要是可以的话
If it's okay...
或许我们应该先多约会几次
Maybe we should hang out more first.
毕竟这是我们除了短信之外
This is only the second conversation we've had
第二次说话
that wasn't by text.
也可能会值得等待
It can also be worth waiting for.
杰 这是什么
Jay, what is this?
不过是你耍我的时候
Just another nice thing I did for you
我为你做的另一件好事罢了
while you made a fool of me.
曼尼把你的小把戏都告诉我了
Manny let me in on your little tricks.
你现在不爽了吗
You feel bad now?
不 我感觉灰常好
No. I feel good.
那照片绝对是我的最爱
That one is definitely my favorite.
菲尔 你真的不必这么做
Phil, you really don't have to do this.
不 我能做到 我想这么做
No. I-I can do it. I wanna do it.
花钱请人来做这个真是太蠢了
It's silly to pay someone else just to do something --
哦 不
Oh, no! Oh!
等等 别别 千万别洒出来
Oh, wait! No, no, don't spill it!
亲爱的 别把它洒出来
Sweetie, don't spill that!
你弄我身上去了
Oh, that's on me!
小心点 我的天啊
Careful! Oh, gosh!
没事的 站起来 你没事的
Okay, get up. You're fine.
-把它弄掉 -好的 我来弄
- Get it off! - Okay, I got it.
我来弄 脱掉了 脱掉了
I got it. Got it off. Got it off.
-我的脸 -没弄你的脸
- Oh, the face! - Not the face!
-我的脸 -看到了
- Oh, the face! - All right,
我会帮你擦掉的 你没事的
I'll pull it down! You're good!
好吧 我得去
All right, I'm gonna have to
-弄得我一身都是 -我来把衣服剪了
- It's on me. - I'll cut it off.
好主意
Good idea.
帮我拿个桶 快点
Get a bucket, please!